Personal Information



+66 84 518 1332



siriwuttho@gmail.com

Date of Birth: August 1990 Nationality: Thai Address: Saphan Sung, Bangkok, Thailand, 10250

Skills

Problem solving using data

Process Improvement

Sharp Decision-making

Project Management

Team building

Adaptive and flexible

Data Analytics

- SQL
- Power BI
- Python (basic)

Statistical and Numerical Analysis Skills

Computer literacy (Microsoft Office)

Supply Chain and Logistics Management

Third-Party Logistics (3PL) Management

Cross border logistics Experiences

Strategy planning and formulation

Budget planning

Language Proficiency

Thai:						
English: IELTS Overall 6.5 (Listening 6.0 Reading 6.5 Writing 6.0 Speaking 7.0)						
Laos:						
Chinese:						
Vietnamese-						



SIRIWUT SIRIPHUWAROJ

Operation Excellence and Solutions Manager, Pomelo Fashion

I am passionate about insight-finding using analytical concepts and systematic thinking and problem-solving, having data to support my decisions. I have been working in multicultural environments in Thailand and overseas. So, I be aware of working with different people personalities and engage team members. My Areas of expertise are project management, process improvement, operation management, and strategic planning. I am also interested in corporate finance and FinTech.

Education

Asian Institute of Technology (AIT)

Thailand

Aug 2020 - Jul 2022

School of Management

Master of Business Administration, Specialize in Finance Royal Thai Government Scholarship (full scholarship)

Faculty of Engineering

Bachelor of Industrial Engineering

Khon Kaen University

Thailand

Jun 2009 - Mar 2013

Work Experience

Operations Excellence and Solutions Manager

Mar 2023 - Present

Operations, Pomelo Fashion

- Optimize all ops functions along with P&L by developing and applying datadriven strategies
- Supervise and develop operation dashboard to monitor performance
- Act as an in-house business intelligence to facilitate and find insights for Ops
- Support continuous improvement and identify inefficiencies and cost optimization opportunities
- Operation excellence, process improvement, and control tower
- Operation **budget** planning and strategy formulation

Regional Logistics Manager

Jan 2022 - Feb 2023

Operations, Pomelo Fashion

- Leading the regional logistics functions (ASEAN and global markets) and overseeing all x-border & in-country distributions, fulfillment, and returns in terms of strategy & 3PL mgmt.
- Building & managing the team effectively to achieve top-in-class regional ecommerce & Direct-2-Retail (D2R) logistics performance.
- Managing Pomelo's regional logistics network and continuously evolving the landscape to create a competitive advantage.
- Strategize & improve regional logistics model to achieve the best solution in duty & taxes reduction.
- Recommend **new logistics routing advise** of cost implications and efficiency
- Logistics cost management

Data Analytics Catalyst Lead

May 2021 - Dec 2021

Corporate Innovation Office, The Siam Cement PCL (SCG)

- Project manager, Corporate data management across SCG project
- Data-driven culture accelerator and facilitator
- Data analytics project lead

Business Initiatives and Executions Manager (Expat in China) Jun 2018 - Apr 2021

Overseas Business, SCG Logistics Management Co., Ltd

- Develop new businesses for a new JV company in China and Thailand (SCG and JUSDA, FOXCONN)
- China-ASEAN cross-border transport operation management
- Design and Develop cross border transport service solutions between China and **ASEAN** countries
- Business strategy development and improvement (Short/Long term Plan)
- Develop and Execute supply chain and logistics strategies

Interest

Supply Chain Management

Technology

Strategy and marketing

Business Development

Learning Process

Self-Improvement

Grants and Awards

ANQ Congress 2015 Taipei, Taiwan **Best Paper Award** on Reduce waste time in Paper rolls transpiration

Royal Thai Government Full Scholarship (RTG) for MBA at Asian Institute of Technology (AIT)

Certificates

- SQL for Data Science, UC Davis, Coursera
- Introduction to Data Studio, Google Analytics Academy
- Google Data Analytics for Beginners, Google Analytics Academy
- Microsoft Power BI Desktop for Business Intelligence, Udemy
- The Business Intelligence Analyst Course 2021, Udemy
- Project Management Foundations, Linkedin Learning
- Data Science for Everyone DataCamp

Work Experience

Country Associate Manager (Expat in Vietnam)

Apr 2018 - May 2018

Overseas Business, SCG Logistics Management Co.,Ltd

- Business analyst and development in Cement and Building Materials Business
- Explore and study a logistic operation for Cement plants in Vietnam

Country Associate Manager (Expat in Laos)

Jun 2017 - Mar 2018

Overseas Business, SCG Logistics Management Co.,Ltd

- Business analyst and development of SCG Logistics (Lao)
- Financial and Accounting control and Administrative management
- · Logistics operational process improvement
- Acquire new customers to expand the company's network and businesses in Laos
- Business strategy development and planning

Export Warehouse Lead

Oct 2016 - May 2017

Operation Department, SCG Logistics Management Co., Ltd

- Export/Import warehouse operations
- Design and improve warehouse processes
- Reduce waiting time for trucks and improve warehouse efficiency in peak periods i.e. Thai and Chinese New Year (Jan-April)

Logistics Planning Center

Aug 2016 - Sep 2016

Operation Department, SCG Logistics Management Co.,Ltd

- Logistics cost structure analysis for small trucks
- Set up cost structure tables for ready-to-use calculation
- Improve truck fleet utilization and develop a fleet-sharing platform

Logistics Account Executive (Business Development) Jul 2015 – Jul 201

Sales and Marketing Department, SCG Logistics Management Co.,Ltd

- Design and promote the company's services to clients in the packaging business
- Cooperate with Process improvement and Operation team for improving existing logistics services
- Analyze business opportunities and implement them to expand the coverage and network of this business
- Team lead of transport and warehouse services bidding (won 5 of 10 biddings) with a value of 100,000,000 THB per year
- · Business strategic planning and development

Logistics Engineer and Analyst

Apr 2013 – Jun 2015

Operation Department, SCG Logistics Management Co.,Ltd

- Logistics process improvement
- Identify and reduce waiting time in transport and warehouse as well as find opportunities to optimize total logistic processes
- Introduce a newly designed truck, a side-curtain truck as a project manager with project value of 200,000,000 THB
- Support business strategic planning and development (annual and mediumterm plan)